<sect1 id="ch06-tagging">
<title>Adding Tags</title>
<?dbhtml filename="tagging.html" dir="chapter06"?>

<itemizedlist>

<listitem><para>acronym -- a word formed from the initial letter or
letters of each of the successive parts or major parts of a compound
term.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>filename -- a filename, a fully qualified file name, a
directory (use class="directory"), a library file (use
class="libraryfile") or an extension (do not use class="extension" as it
was added in DocBook XML DTD V4.2). Extensions should be written in all
caps as many are also acronyms.  Do not encapsulate an acronym tag with
a filename tag, use either/or based on the usage.</para>
<para>These classes should not be used until the XML header is updated to
V4.2 -- devicefile, headerfile, partition and symlink.  They do,
however, describe other files that should be tagged.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>envar -- an environmental variable, can be common or
temporary.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>command -- any string that will execute when entered at
the prompt (not just bash prompts).</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>userinput -- usually encapsulates "command" when it is
expected that the user is required to input the command to proceed.
"command"s may terminate within userinput to continue showing items that
must be typed in, but are not commands. It is also used when command
options are written without the command, as use
&lt;userinput&gt;-q&lt;/userinput&gt; for quiet operation. A preferable
alternative may be to use the &lt;option&gt; tag.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>application -- The proper name of the package.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>screen -- This creates a 'verbatim' environment that
allows spacing the be controlled. Mainly used as it simulates a
console. It should not be encapsulated by &lt;para&gt; unless unscreened
text is present.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>replaceable -- used with screen to encapsulate text that
is not to be typed as seen or copy and pasted. The text should also be
encapsulated in brackets '[]' for text browser users. It should also be
used outside of the 'screen' where your instructions are for what is to
replace it.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>prompt -- usually used within &lt;screen&gt; to mimic a prompt
that should be seen by the user on his/her screen.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>emphasis role="strong" -- used when an assumption is made
in the instructions that may not always be true, i.e. your network
connection is on &lt;emphasis role=strong&gt;eth0&lt;emphasis&gt;.
Especially prior to giving script instructions using that assumption.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>parameter -- used primarily in the command explanations
section for items that are not commands.</para></listitem>

</itemizedlist>

</sect1>

