<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<!--
$LastChangedBy$
$Date$
-->

<chapter id="cmdline" xreflabel="Command Line Tools">
  <?dbhtml filename="cmdline.html"?>

  <title>Command Line Tools</title>

  <para>These tools are recommended for all systems.</para>

  <para>Openssh provides both an ssh client and a server.  Setting
  up a server allows logging into the system from another system allowing
  control, including building of additional packages, from a full 
  graphical environment.</para>

  <para>Wget allows retrieval of packages from the command line.</para>

  <para>Make-ca provides for installing security certificates of well
  known certificate authorities so applications can properly authenticate
  entities such as an https:// URL across an untrusted network.</para>

  <para>Sudo allows otherwise untrusted users to run commands that 
  require administrative privileges. It is a convenient alternative
  to the su command.</para>

  <para>Which is a convenient utility that shows the full path to a
  command.</para>

  <para>Unzip is an extraction utility for zip files.  It's function is
  similar to gzip. gzip2, and xz that were installed in LFS.</para>

  <para>Links is a text mode WWW browser.  Text mode browsers are
  very fast and can be used before a graphical environment is installed.
  </para>

  <para>Mailx is a a command-line Mail User Agent (MUA).  It is especially
  useful for sending mail messages in scripts.</para>

  <note>
    <para>
      When building BLFS packages, manny will require the installation of
      dependent packages before that are built.  See <xref linkend='dependencies'/>
      to help decide which dependent packages you need.
    </para>
  </note>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="postlfs/security/openssh.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="networking/netprogs/wget.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="postlfs/security/make-ca.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="postlfs/security/sudo.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="general/sysutils/which.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="general/sysutils/unzip.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="networking/textweb/links.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="&xinclude;" href="networking/mailnews/mailx.xml"/>

</chapter>
