<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [

  <!ENTITY blfs-bugzilla "http://blfs-bugs.linuxfromscratch.org">
]>

<chapter id="chapter01">
<chapterinfo>
<othername>$Author$</othername>
<date>$Date$</date>
</chapterinfo>
<title>BLFS Development</title>
<?dbhtml filename="chapter01.html" ?>

<para>The actual BLFS book itself is written using Docbook-XML
(http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/) and at first can seem to be a daunting
tangle of files.  Basically, if you're confused, start by looking at
<filename>index.xml</filename>.  You can see that the files is a well formed
xml file that includes other files.  These included files reflect the
organization of the book.  It is divided into Front Matter, Parts, and
Appendicies.  Parts are divided into Chapters and the Chapters are again
divided into Sections.  Each Section generally represents one application
package.</para>

<para>BLFS development takes place using three main systems.  First, the
mailing lists <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis>, <emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis>, and
(to a lesser extent) <emphasis>blfs-support</emphasis>.  Second, the Bugzilla
tracking system, and third the <application>Subversion</application> server
where the book itself is stored.  All of these services are provided by the
server <emphasis>linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis> also known as
<emphasis>belgarath.linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis>.  This single server
provides mailing lists, web hosting, <application>Subversion</application>
hosting, ftp hosting, the Bugzilla system, and basically everything we use to
work on the BLFS project.</para>

<para>Anyone can subscribe to any of the mailing lists provided by belgarath.
We're not going to describe that (or the lists in detail) here as there is a
good description at <ulink
url="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/mail.html"/>.</para>


<para>The Bugzilla bug-tracking system for BLFS can be found at <ulink
url="&blfs-bugzilla;"/>.  In order to be able to add, remove and edit bugs, you
need to have an account and make sure you are logged in whenever you wish to
perform such an action.  You can query and read the bug database without
logging in or creating a user.  Note that all bugzilla messages are copied to
the <emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis> mailing list and that all editors should be
subscribed to this and the <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis> list at a
minimum.</para>

<para>Finally, there is the Subversion (svn) server which will be discussed in
the following chapters.</para>

</chapter>
