<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE bookinfo PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="chapter03">
<title>Basic SVN Commands</title>
<?dbhtml filename="chapter03.html"?>


<sect1 id="ch03-introduction">
<title>Introduction</title>

<para>The man and info pages of CVS are fairly good but I'm going to list a
basic set of commands which all editors will use on an almost daily basis.
Note that quite a few things can be set in your local
<filename>~/.cvsrc</filename> file.  For example, I have in there: <screen>cvs
-z9 diff -u</screen> This means that all options use the highest level of
compression (I'm on a dial-up link, if you're on broadband it's probably not
needed to do this.  It does entail a slightly higher processing time for both
your machine and shadowfax so think before using it) and says that I always
want the <userinput>cvs diff</userinput> command to use unified diff format
(which <emphasis>all</emphasis> e-mailed submissions (i.e. by those without
write CVS access) to <userinput>blfs-dev</userinput> should use as they're much
easier to read.  There are many more options available, you can usually find
them by doing <userinput>cvs --help</userinput> <emphasis>command</emphasis>.
You can also get a basic list of CVS commands by simply doing <userinput>cvs
--help-commands</userinput>.  Having said all of this, let's get on with the
commands!.</para>

<para>Some commands have two forms, the long and the short.  I'll
list both in the description.</para>

<sect2 id="ch03-checkout">
<title>cvs checkout/co</title>

<para><userinput>cvs checkout</userinput> or <userinput>cvs co</userinput>.
This command is used to pull a CVS tree such as <filename>LFS/BOOK</filename>
(the LFS book) or <filename>BLFS</filename> (the BLFS book) from the server.
You should only need to do this once. If we mess around with the directory
structure (as sometimes is necessary), you may occasionally need to delete your
local sandbox and re-check it out. If this is going to be needed, it will
usually be because the Editor will have made a <emphasis>large</emphasis>
change and it'll be announced at least on the <filename>blfs-book</filename>
list.</para>

</sect2>


<sect2 id="ch03-add">
<title>cvs add</title>

<para><userinput>cvs add</userinput>.  When you are creating a new file,
you need to tell the CVS server about it.  This does that.  Note that
the file won't appear in the repository until you do a <userinput>cvs
commit</userinput> (see below).</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="ch03-delete">
<title>cvs delete/remove</title>

<para><userinput>cvs delete</userinput> or <userinput>cvs
remove</userinput>.  This does what it says!  Note
that you have to have deleted the file locally before you can run this.
Again, the file will not be deleted from the server until you do a
<userinput>cvs commit</userinput>.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="ch03-update">
<title>cvs update/up</title>

<para><userinput>cvs update</userinput> or <userinput>cvs
up</userinput>.  This command syncs your local sandbox with the server.
If you have made local changes, it'll try and merge any changes on the
server with your changes <emphasis>on your machine</emphasis>.  You
should always do a manual <userinput>cvs update</userinput> before
trying to commit changes in order to check that everything is alright
and ready to go (although when you do a <userinput>cvs
commit</userinput>, it will warn you if there is a problem).</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="ch03-commit">
<title>cvs commit/ci</title>

<para><userinput>cvs commit</userinput> or <userinput>cvs
ci</userinput>.  This command recursively sends your changes to the CVS
server.  It will commit changed files, added files and deleted files.
The -m option can be used to pass a log message to the command.  If you
don't specify a -m "MESSAGE", then it will open vi (you may be able to
override this using the $EDITOR variable but I've never tried it).
Please don't use empty log messages (see later in this document on the
policy which governs them).</para>

</sect2>

<sect2 id="ch03-diff">
<title>cvs diff</title>

<para><userinput>cvs diff</userinput>.  This is useful for two different
purposes.  Firstly, those without write access to the BLFS CVS server
can use it to generate patches to send to
<userinput>blfs-dev</userinput>.  To do this, simply edit the files in
your local sandbox then run <userinput>cvs diff -u &gt;
FILE.patch</userinput> from the root of your BLFS directory.  You can
then attach this file to a message to <userinput>blfs-dev</userinput>
where someone with editing rights will pick it up and apply it to the
book.  The second use is to find out what has changed between two
revisions using:
<userinput>cvs diff -u -r revision1 -r revision2 FILENAME</userinput>.
For example: <userinput>cvs diff -u -r 1.68 -r 1.69
index.xml</userinput> will output a unified diff showing the changes
between revisions 1.68 and 1.69 of <filename>index.xml</filename>.
Remember that when using cvs diff, you nearly
<emphasis>always</emphasis> want to output a unified diff and so either
use the <userinput>-u</userinput> switch or add it to
your <userinput>~/.cvsrc</userinput></para>

</sect2>


<sect2 id="ch03-moving">
<title>Moving files</title>

<para>Moving files:  One of the (many?) complaints against cvs is that
it has no concept of 1) moving files or 2) versioning directories.  If
you need to move a file, it's generally better to do it on the server
manually.  <emphasis>If this is needed, please contact me and I'll do
it</emphasis>.  This is simply because then if something goes wrong,
it's me who takes the fall instead of anyone else!</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>


</chapter>
