<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" >

<chapter id="chapter07">
<chapterinfo>
<othername>$Author$</othername>
<date>$Date$</date>
</chapterinfo>
<title>Overall editing policy</title>
<?dbhtml filename="chapter07.html"?>

<para>This section needs further development. Suggestions are welcome.</para>

<section id="ch07-apps">
<title>Adding Applications</title>
<para>To be developed.  When should new apps be added to the book.</para>
</section>

<section id='ch07-build-instructions'>
<title>Build Instructions</title>

<para>When developing instructions to build a package, the editor should
recommend a preferred build method&mdash;one that is reliable, stable, and performs
well.  The editor uses his best judgement to determine the appropriate switches
and methodology for the typical user in each section.  In some cases, the
number of options is large and there should be a note placed in the text to
tell the user to consult other documentaion for additional options.
</para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-optimization">
<title>Optimization</title>

<para>Generally custom optimization beyond the application's default
optimization should not be encouraged.  It generally causes more problems than
it is worth.  In some cases, certain optimizations may be recommended, but this
should be done with appropriate warnings.</para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-patches">
<title>Patches</title>
<para>Patches are maintained in a separate patches svn repository.  All BLFS
editors have commit privileges to this repository.  To check out the patch tree,
start in an empty directory and run:</para>

<screen><command>svn co svn+ssh://linuxfromscratch.org/patches/trunk/</command></screen>

<para>and then using normal svn procedures.</para>

<para>When inserting a patch
in the book, or changing an existing patch, the first choice is to point
to the package originator's site.  If a custom patch is needed for BLFS,
it should be placed in the apprpriate location of the patches repository.
A patch must always go in a directory of the same name as the base package
without revision numbers.  For instance, all mysql patches go in the mysql
directory of the patches repository.</para>

<para>The location of BLFS patches in the book will always be at 
&amp;patch-root;.  The location is updated twice a day automatically when 
the book renders.</para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-scripts">
<title>Scripts</title>
<para>To be developed.  </para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-anduin">
<title>BLFS Packages</title>
<para>The BLFS project has a web/ftp site at anduin.linuxfromscratch.org. 
This site is a repository for all the packages with build instructions
in BLFS.  When adding or upgrading a package in the book, the new package should be
placed in the appropriate directory there.  If necessary, repackage the
source code as a .bz2 file before upgrading.  Old versions of the package
should be deleted. Also create a separate
file that contains the md5sum of the tarball:</para>

<screen><command>md5sum packagename.tar.bz2 > packagename.tar.bz2.md5sum</command></screen>

<para>If a package has multiple files or patches, they should all be placed in 
the same directory and md5sums calculated for all files:</para>

<screen><command>rm packagename*md5sum
md5sum packagename-x.x* > packagename-x.x.md5sums</command></screen>

</section>

<section id="ch07-tagging">
<title>Adding Tags</title>

<itemizedlist>

<listitem><para>acronym -- a word formed from the initial letter or
letters of each of the successive parts or major parts of a compound
term. Try to avoid using this tag inside other inline tags because
it really does not add any additional value and the XML becomes hard
to read.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>filename -- a filename, a fully qualified file name, a
directory (use class="directory"), a library file (use
class="libraryfile").</para>

<para>Other extentions that may be used are extention, devicefile, headerfile,
partition and symlink.  These are not normally used, but could be used to define
a file type.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>systemitem -- similar to filename, but for items thar aren't files.
Examples are usernames (use class="username"), groups (use class="groupname"),
filesystems (use class="filesystem"), etc.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>envar -- an environmental variable, can be common or
temporary.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>command -- used to tag commands names, commands (with their
parameters) in the "Command Explanations" section, or commands that are 
optional.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>userinput -- encapsulates commands when it is
expected that the user is required to input the command exactly as specified.
Used mainly in screen blocks.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>option -- Should be used in the flow text when command
options are written without the command, as use
&lt;option&gt;-q&lt;/option&gt; for quiet operation. It is also used in the 
"Commands Explanations" sections for optional switches.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>application -- The proper name of the package.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>screen -- This creates a 'verbatim' environment that
allows spacing to be controlled. Mainly used when a simulated 
console is desired. It can be encapsulated by &lt;para&gt; tags but 
provides little value. Try to avoid this.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>replaceable -- used with screen to encapsulate text that
is not to be typed as seen or copy and pasted. The text should be
encapsulated in brackets '[]' for text browser users. It should not be
used in 'screen' sections.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>literal -- used with userinput in screen sections to 
encapsulate text that will be used to create (or to be added to) a 
text file.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>emphasis role="strong" -- used to emphasize some word when 
there is no other appropiate tag that can be used or when an assumption is made in
the instructions that may not always be true. For example, your network connection is
on &lt;emphasis role=strong&gt;eth0&lt;emphasis&gt;.  Especially prior to
giving script instructions using that assumption.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>parameter -- used primarily in the command explanations
section for items that are not commands but used in the installation commands
provided by the book. An example of this use is when explaining 
<command>configure</command> switches.</para></listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<note><para>There are several ways to use the userinput, command, option,
replaceable, parameter, envar, constant, varname, etc., tags.  Don't overdo it.
In many cases, the tags will not change the output and will make editing the
XML text more difficult.  Generally, a single set of tags around a block of
text is sufficient.</para></note>

</section>


</chapter>
