<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="chapter03">
  <chapterinfo>
    <othername>$Author$</othername>
    <date>$Date$</date>
  </chapterinfo>
  <title>Basic SVN Commands</title>
  <?dbhtml filename="chapter03.html"?>

  <section id="ch03-introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The help function of <application>Subversion</application>
    (<command>svn help</command>) provides a summary of the available commands.
    More detailed information is available from the
    <application>Subversion</application> on-line book available at <ulink
    url='http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/index.html'/>. Chapter 3 is especially
    helpful.</para>

    <para>The following is a basic set of commands which all editors will use
    frequently.  Some commands have two forms, the long and the short.  Both are
    listed in the description.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-checkout">
    <title>svn checkout/co</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.checkout.html">
    <command>svn checkout</command></ulink> or <command>svn co</command>.
    This command is used to pull an SVN tree such as
    <userinput>svn://linuxfromscratch.org/BLFS/trunk/BOOK</userinput> (the
    BLFS Development book) from the server.  You should only need to do this
    once. If the directory structure is changed (as is sometimes necessary),
    you <emphasis>may</emphasis> occasionally need to delete your local sand
    box and re-check it out. If this is going to be needed, it will usually be
    because the Editor will have made a <emphasis>large</emphasis> change and
    it will be announced at least on the BLFS-Book mailing list.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-add">
    <title>svn add</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.add.html">
    <command>svn add</command></ulink>.  When you are creating a new file or
    directory, you need to tell the SVN server about it. This command does
    that.  Note that the file won't appear in the repository until you do an
    <command>svn commit</command> (see below).</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-propset">
    <title>svn propset</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.propset.html">
    <command>svn propset</command></ulink>.  When you are creating a new file
    or directory, you generally need to tell the SVN to apply properties to the
    file in places that have keywords in a special format such as
    <computeroutput>$Date$</computeroutput>.
    Note that the keyword value won't appear in the file until you do an
    <command>svn commit</command> (see below).</para>

    <para>Normally, the command you want is
<screen><userinput>svn propset svn:keywords "Date LastChangedBy" /path/to/filename.xml</userinput></screen>
    </para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-delete">
    <title>svn delete</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.delete.html">
    <command>svn delete</command></ulink>.  This does what it says!  When you
    do an <command>svn commit</command> the file will be deleted from your local
    sand box immediately as well as from the repository after committing.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-status">
    <title>svn status</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.status.html">
    <command>svn status</command></ulink>.  This command prints the status of
    working directories and files.  If you have made local changes, it'll show your
    locally modified items.  If you use the <parameter>--verbose</parameter>
    switch, it will show revision information on every item.  With the
    <parameter>--show-updates</parameter> (<parameter>-u</parameter>) switch,
    it will show any server out-of-date information.</para>

    <para>You should always do a manual <command>svn status
    --show-updates</command> before trying to commit changes in order to check
    that everything is OK and ready to go.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-update">
    <title>svn update/up</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.update.html">
    <command>svn update</command></ulink> or <command>svn up</command>. This
    command syncs your local sand box with the server. If you have made local
    changes, it will try and merge any changes on the server with your changes
    <emphasis>on your machine</emphasis>.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-commit">
    <title>svn commit/ci</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.commit.html">
    <command>svn commit</command></ulink> or <command>svn ci</command>. This
    command recursively sends your changes to the SVN server.  It will commit
    changed files, added files, and deleted files. Note that you can commit
    a change to an individual file or changes to files in a specific directory
    path by adding the name of the file/directory to the end of the command.
    The <parameter>-m</parameter> option should always be used to pass a log
    message to the command.  Please don't use empty log messages (see later in
    this document the policy which governs the log messages).</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-diff">
    <title>svn diff</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.diff.html">
    <command>svn diff</command></ulink>. This is useful for two different
    purposes.  First, those without write access to the BLFS SVN server can use
    it to generate patches to send to the BLFS-Dev mailing list. To do this,
    simply edit the files in your local sand box then run
    <command>svn diff &gt; FILE.patch</command> from the root of your BLFS
    directory. You can then attach this file to a message to the BLFS-Dev
    mailing list where someone with editing rights can pick it up and apply it
    to the book.  The second use is to find out what has changed between two
    revisions using:
    <command>svn diff -r revision1:revision2 FILENAME</command>.  For example:
    <command>svn diff -r 168:169 index.xml</command> will output a diff showing
    the changes between revisions 168 and 169 of
    <filename>index.xml</filename>.</para>

  </section>

  <section id="ch03-moving">
    <title>svn move</title>

    <para><ulink
    url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.2/svn.ref.svn.c.move.html">
    <command>svn move SRC DEST</command></ulink> or
    <command>svn mv SRC DEST</command> or
    <command>svn rename SRC DEST</command> or
    <command>svn ren SRC DEST</command>. This command moves a file from one
    directory to another or renames a file. The file will be moved on your
    local sand box immediately as well as on the repository after
    committing.</para>

  </section>

</chapter>
