<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" >

<chapter id="chapter07">
<chapterinfo>
<othername>$Author$</othername>
<date>$Date$</date>
</chapterinfo>
<title>Overall editing policy</title>
<?dbhtml filename="chapter07.html"?>

<para>This section needs further development. Suggestions are welcome.</para>

<section id="ch07-apps">
<title>Adding Applications</title>
<para>To be developed.  When should new apps be added to the book.</para>
</section>

<section id='ch07-build-instructions'>
<title>Build Instructions</title>

<para>When developing instructions to build a package, the editor should
recommend a preferred build method&mdash;one that is reliable, stable, and performs
well.  The editor uses his best judgement to determine the appropriate switches
and methodology for the typical user in each section.  In some cases, the
number of options is large and there should be a note placed in the text to
tell the user to consult other documentaion for additional options.
</para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-optimization">
<title>Optimization</title>

<para>Generally custom optimization beyond the application's default
optimization should not be encouraged.  It generally causes more problems than
it is worth.  In some cases, certain optimizations may be recommended, but this
should be done with appropriate warnings.</para> 
</section>

<section id="ch07-patches">
<title>Patches</title>
<para>To be developed.  </para>
</section>

<section id="ch07-scripts">
<title>Scripts</title>
<para>To be developed.  </para>
</section>


<section id="ch07-tagging">
<title>Adding Tags</title>

<itemizedlist>

<listitem><para>acronym -- a word formed from the initial letter or
letters of each of the successive parts or major parts of a compound
term.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>filename -- a filename, a fully qualified file name, a
directory (use class="directory"), a library file (use
class="libraryfile"). Do not encapsulate an acronym tag with
a filename tag, use either/or based on the usage.</para>

<para>Other extentions that may be used are extention, devicefile, headerfile,
partition and symlink.  These are not normally used, but could be used in the
future in the rendering process.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>envar -- an environmental variable, can be common or
temporary.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>command -- any string that will execute when entered at
the prompt (not just bash prompts).</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>userinput -- usually encapsulates "command" when it is
expected that the user is required to input the command to proceed.
"command"s may terminate within userinput to continue showing items that
must be typed in, but are not commands. </para></listitem>

<listitem><para>option -- Should be used when command
options are written without the command, as use
&lt;option&gt;-q&lt;/option&gt; for quiet operation.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>application -- The proper name of the package.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>screen -- This creates a 'verbatim' environment that
allows spacing to be controlled. Mainly used as it simulates a
console. It should not be encapsulated by &lt;para&gt; unless unscreened
text is present.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>replaceable -- used with screen to encapsulate text that
is not to be typed as seen or copy and pasted. The text should also be
encapsulated in brackets '[]' for text browser users. It should also be
used outside of the 'screen' where your instructions are for what is to
replace it.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>emphasis role="strong" -- used when an assumption is made in
the instructions that may not always be true, i.e. your network connection is
on &lt;emphasis role=strong&gt;eth0&lt;emphasis&gt;.  Especially prior to
giving script instructions using that assumption.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>parameter -- used primarily in the command explanations
section for items that are not commands.</para></listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<note><para>There are several ways to use the userinput, command, option,
replaceable, parameter, envar, constant, varname, etc., tags.  Don't overdo it.
In many cases, the tags will not change the output and will make editing the
XML text more difficult.  Generally, a single set of tags around a block of
text is sufficient.</para></note>

</section>


</chapter>
