<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE bookinfo PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [

  <!ENTITY blfs-bugzilla "http://blfs-bugs.linuxfromscratch.org">
]>

<chapter id="chapter01">
<title>BLFS Development</title>
<?dbhtml filename="chapter01.html" ?>

<para>BLFS development takes place using three main systems.  Firstly, the
mailing lists <emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis>, <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis> and
(to a lesser extent) <emphasis>blfs-support</emphasis>.  Secondly the Bugzilla
tracking system, and thirdly the <application>Subversion</application> server
where the book itself is stored.  All of these services are provided by the
server <emphasis>linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis> also known as
<emphasis>belgarath.linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis>.  This single server
provides mailing lists, web hosting, <application>Subversion</application>
hosting, ftp hosting, the Bugzilla system and basically everything we use to
work on the BLFS project.</para>

<para>The actual BLFS book itself is written using Docbook-XML and at first can
seem to be a daunting tangle of files.  Basically, if you're confused, start by
looking at <filename>index.xml</filename>.  At the bottom, you will notice that
it will reference the entity &amp;book;.  Look up the entity &amp;book; and you
will see that it points to the file <filename>book/book.xml</filename>.
Continue in this way and you'll soon be finding your way around the book like a
pro!</para>

<para>Anyone can subscribe to any of the mailing lists provided by shadowfax.
I'm not going to describe that (or the lists in detail) here as there is a good
description at <ulink
url="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/mailinglists/info.shtml"/>.</para>

<para>The Bugzilla bug-tracking system for BLFS can be found at <ulink
url="&blfs-bugzilla;"/>.  In order to be able to
add, remove and edit bugs, you need to add an account and make sure you
are logged in whenever you wish to perform such an action.  You can
query and read the bug database without logging in or creating a user.
Note that all bugzilla messages are copied to the
<emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis> mailing list and that all editors
should be subscribed to this and the <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis>
list at a minimum.</para>

<para>Finally, there is the CVS server which will be discussed in the
following chapters.</para>

</chapter>
