<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<chapter id="chapter01">
  <chapterinfo>
    <othername>$Author$</othername>
    <date>$Date$</date>
  </chapterinfo>
  <title>BLFS Development</title>
  <?dbhtml filename="chapter01.html" ?>

  <para>The actual BLFS book itself is written using Docbook-XML
  (http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/) and at first can seem to be a daunting
  tangle of files.  Basically, if you're confused, start by looking at
  <filename>index.xml</filename>.  You can see that the file is a well formed
  xml file that includes other files.  These included files reflect the
  organization of the book.  It is divided into Front Matter, Parts, and
  Appendices.  Parts are divided into Chapters and the Chapters are again
  divided into Sections.  Each Section generally represents one specific
  topic.</para>

  <para>BLFS development takes place using three main systems.  First, the
  mailing lists <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis>, <emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis>,
  and (to a lesser extent) <emphasis>blfs-support</emphasis>.  Second, the Trac
  Wiki and ticket tracking system, and third the
  <application>Subversion</application> repository where the book itself is stored.
  All of these services are provided by the server
  <emphasis>linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis> also known as
  <emphasis>quantum.linuxfromscratch.org</emphasis>.  This single server provides
  mailing lists, web hosting, <application>Subversion</application> hosting, ftp
  hosting, the Trac system, and basically everything used to work on the BLFS
  project.</para>

  <para>Anyone can subscribe to any of the mailing lists provided by quantum.
  You can find a good description of the mailing lists at <ulink
  url="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/mail.html"/>.</para>

  <para>The Trac Wiki and ticket tracking system for BLFS can be found at <ulink
  url="&blfs-trac;"/>.  In order to be able to add, remove and edit tickets, you
  need to have an account and make sure you are logged in whenever you wish to
  perform such an action.  You can query and read the ticket database without
  logging in or creating a user.  Note that all Trac tickets are copied to
  the <emphasis>blfs-book</emphasis> mailing list and that all editors should be
  subscribed to this and the <emphasis>blfs-dev</emphasis> list at a
  minimum.</para>

  <para>Finally, there is the Subversion (svn) server which will be discussed in
  the following chapters.</para>

</chapter>
